A Guide to the Correspondence and Subject Files of the Secretary of the Commonwealth, 2014-2022.
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Correspondence and Subject Files of the Secretary of the Commonwealth,
2018-2022.
The Library of Virginia
53535
Virginia. Secretary of the Commonwealth.
XX cu. ft. (XX boxes)
Administrative Information
Arranged by series.
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions
Acquisition Information
Accession 53505 was transferred by the Office of the Secretary of the Commonwealth, Jan 21, 2022.
Historical Information
XX
Scope and Content
Topics include but are not limited to appointments, electronic notarization, legislation, Millennial Civic Engagement Task Force, Commonwealth Commission on Diversity, Equity and Inclusion, and restoration of rights.
Records may include agendas, correspondence, executive order, legislation, meeting records, notes, oaths of office, talking points, reports.
Contents List
- Correspondence and Subject Files of the Secretary of the Commonwealth - McAuliffe Administration, 2014-2018.
  - Series I: Secretary of the Commonwealth, 2014-2018., Extent: XX cu. ft.
    Includes correspondence and subject files of Secretary of the Commonwealth Levar Stoney (2014-2016) and Secretary of the Commonwealth Kelly Thomasson (2016-2018) during the administration of Governor Terrence McAuliffe. Includes files for appointments, electronic notarization, executive orders, legislation, Millennial Civic Engagement Task Force, Commonwealth Commission on Diversity, Equity and Inclusion, and restoration of rights, among others. Appointment files consist mainly of recommendation letters for appointment or reappointment to college and university boards of visitors. Commonwealth Commission on Diversity, Equity and Inclusion include correspondence, meeting records, oaths of office for commission members, planning documentation, and talking points. Legislative files include legislation, legislative action summaries, and planning documentation. Millennial Civic Engagement Task Force records include correspondence, forum and planning documentation, meeting records, and reports. Restoration of rights files include correspondence, announcement records related to Gov. McAuliffe's Restoration of Rights Order, 2016; as well as policy change and research documentation.
    - Appointments - Board of Education, 2014-2016. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Appointments - Christopher Newport University, 2014. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Appointments - Christopher Newport University, 2015. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Appointments - Christopher Newport University, 2016. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Appointments - Christopher Newport University, 2017. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Appointments - College of William and Mary, 2014. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Appointments - College of William and Mary, 2015. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Appointments - College of William and Mary, 2016. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Appointments - College of William and Mary, 2017. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Appointments - George Mason University, 2014. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Appointments - George Mason University, 2015. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Appointments - George Mason University, 2016-2017. (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Appointments - James Madison University, 2014-2016. (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Appointments - Norfolk State University, 2014. (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Appointments - Norfolk State University, 2015, 2017. (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Appointments - Old Dominion University, 2014. (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Appointments - Old Dominion University, 2015. (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Appointments - Old Dominion University, 2016-2017. (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Appointments - Radford University, 2014-2017. (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Appointments - State Board for Community Colleges, 2014-2015. (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Appointments - State Board for Community Coleges, 2016. (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Appointments - State Board for Community Colleges, 2017. (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Appointments - State Council of Higher Education for Virginia, 2014. (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Appointments - State Council of Higher Education for Virginia, 2015. (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Appointments - State Council of Higher Education for Virginia, 2016-2017. (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Appointments - Mary Washington University, 2014. (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Appointments - Mary Washington University, 2015. (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Appointments - Mary Washington University, 2016-2017. (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Appointments - University of Virginia, 2014. (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Appointments - University of Virginia, 2015. (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Appointments - University of Virginia, 2016-2017. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Appointments - Virginia Commission for Higher Education, 2014. (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Appointments - Virginia Commonwealth University, 2014. (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Appointments - Virginia Commonwealth University, 2015. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Appointments - Virginia Commonwealth University, 2016. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Appointments - Virginia Commonwealth University, 2017. (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Appointments - Virginia Military Institute, 2014. (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Appointments - Virginia Military Institute, 2015-2017. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Appointments - Virginia State University, 2015-2016. (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Appointments - Virginia Tech, 2014. (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Appointments - Virginia Tech, 2015. (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Appointments - Virginia Tech, 2016. (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Appointments - Virginia Tech, 2017. (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Appointments - Miscellaneous, 2015-2017. (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Certificates of Election, 2013. (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Conflict of Interest, 2014. (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence - Miscellaneous, 2017. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Customer Relationship Management (CRM) - VITA, 2014-2017. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Elections, State Board of - Electors for President and Vice President, 2017. (Box 3, Folder 3a)
    - Ethics Advisory Council, 2015-2016. (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Executive Orders, 2014. (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Extraditions, 2012. (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Legislative Session, 2015. (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Legislative Session, 2016. (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Legislative Session, 2017. (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Millennial Civic Engagement Task Force, 2014-2018. (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Miscellaneous, 2014-2018. (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Notaries, 2017. (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Notarization - Electronic, 2015. (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Notarization - Electronic (McDonnell), 2008-2010. (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Notarization - NASS Remote Notarization Task Force, 2017. (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Pardons - Miscellaneous, 2014-2017. (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Racial Reconciliation - Commonwealth Commission on Diversity, Equity and Inclusion, 2017-2019. (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Restoration of Rights, 2014. (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Restoration of Rights, 2015. (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Restoration of Rights, 2016. (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Restoration of Rights, undated. (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Restoration of Rights - Announcement, 2016 Apr 22. (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Restoration of Rights - Howell v. McAuliffe, 2016. (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Restoration of Rights - Policy changes, 2014-2016. (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Restoration of Rights - Research, 2014-2018. (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Seal of Virginia (McDonnell), 2011. (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Speech, undated. (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Virginia Women's Summit, 2017. (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Series I: Secretary of the Commonwealth, 2016-2017., Extent: .25 cu. ft.
    Correspondence and subject files of Deputy Secretary Traci DeShazor, 2016-2017. Records of the Commonwealth Commission on Diversity, Equity and Inclusion include a draft interim report, 2017 Dec; signed oaths of office for commission members, 2017 Oct; and a memo related to the anniversary of the tragic events in Charlottesville, undated. Millenial Civic Engagement Task Force records include a 2017 Report on the State of Millennial Civic Engagement in the Commonwealth; Proposal to Re-establish a Campus Compact, 2017; proposals, meeting records, and signed oaths of office for task force members, 2017 July.
    - Constituent correspondence, 20. (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Commonwealth Commission on Diversity, Equity and Inclusion, 2016-2017. (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Millennial Civic Engagement Task Force, 2016-2017. (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Correspondence and Subject Files of the Secretary of the Commonwealth - Northam Administration, 2018-2022.
  - Series I: Secretary of the Commonwealth Kelly Thomasson, 2018-2022., Extent: XX cu. ft.
    Correspondence and subject files of Secretary of the Commonwealth Kelly Thomasson include correspondence, Topics include appointments
    Appointment files consists of letters of recommendation for appointment or reappointment to various boards and commissions, the majority of which are for college and university boards of visitors.
    - Correspondence, 2018. (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 2019 Jan-Feb. (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 2019 Mar. (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 2019 Apr-May. (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 2019 June-Nov. (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, 2019 Dec. (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, 2020. (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, 2021. (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, undated. (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Advisory Boards - Budget, undated. (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - African American Advisory Board, 2019. (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Appointments, 2018 Jan-Feb. (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Appointments, 2018 Mar. (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Appointments, 2018 Apr-Dec. (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Appointments, 2019 Jan-Mar. (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Appointments, 2019 Apr-June. (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Appointments, 2019 July-Dec. (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Appointments, 2020 Jan-Feb. (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Appointments, 2020 Mar-June. (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Appointments, 2020 July-Dec. (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Appointments, 2021. (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Appointments - Miscellaneous and Oaths, 2018-2021. (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Cannabis Public Health Advisory Council, 2021. (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Census / Virginia Complete the Count Commission, 2018 Aug 29. (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Census / Virginia Complete the Count Commission, 2018 Dec 18. (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Census / Virginia Complete the Count Commission, 2019 Jan 22. (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Census / Virginia Complete the Count Commission, 2019 Feb 27. (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Census / Virginia Complete the Count Commission, 2019 Mar 28. (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Census / Virginia Complete the Count Commission, 2019 Apr 30. (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Census / Virginia Complete the Count Commission, 2019 May 1. (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Census / Virginia Complete the Count Commission, 2019 June 25. (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Census / Virginia Complete the Count Commission, 2019 Aug 21. (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Census / Virginia Complete the Count Commission, 2019 Sept 24. (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Census / Virginia Complete the Count Commission, 2019 Nov 14. (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Census / Virginia Complete the Count Commission, 2019 Dec 17. (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Census / Virginia Complete the Count Commission, 2020 Feb 3. (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Census / Virginia Complete the Count Commission, 2020 Mar 2. (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Census / Virginia Complete the Count Commission - Binder (U.S. Census Bureau), 2020. (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Census / Virginia Complete the Count Commission - Census Bureau, U.S., 2019-2020. (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Census / Virginia Complete the Count Commission - Executive Order and membership, 2018. (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Census / Virginia Complete the Count Commission - Local and State Government Toolkit, undated. (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Census / Virginia Complete the Count Commission - Meeting with Weldon Cooper Center, 2020 Feb 14. (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Census / Virginia Complete the Count Commission - Miscellaneous, 2019-2020. (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Census / Virginia Complete the Count Commission - Notes, 2019-2020. (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Census / Virginia Complete the Count Commission - Oaths, 2018-2019. (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Census / Virginia Complete the Count Commission - Partnership proposals, 2019. (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Commission to Examine Racial Inequity in Virginia Law, 2019. (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Constituent Services and Community Engagement, 2019. (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Constituent Services Restructure, 2018. (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Diversity, Equity and Inclusion, Office of, 2018-2019. (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Fishback cases, 2018-2020. (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Girl Scouts, 2018. (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Indian Advisory Board, 2017 Sept 6. (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Indian Advisory Board, 2017 Oct 25. (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Indian Advisory Board, 2017 Nov 8. (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Indian Advisory Board, 2018 Jan 10. (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Indian Advisory Board, 2021 Oct 7. (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Indian Advisory Board, 2021 Oct 27. (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Indian Advisory Board, 2021 Nov 15. (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Indian Advisory Board, 2021 Dec 2. (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Indian Commemorative Commission, 2016-2018. (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Indian Tribes - Basic Briefing on Virginia Indians for Legislators, Government Officials and Staff, 2013. (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Indian Tribes - Census, 2017. (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Indian Tribes - Federally Recognized Tribes meeting, 2018 July 13. (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Indian Tribes - Federally Recognized Tribes meeting, 2018 Sept 7. (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - Indian Tribes - Gateway to Werowocomoco at Timberneck Farms, 2018 Mar 6. (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - Indian Tribes - A History of the Defense Supply Center Richmond: From Native Americans to America's Defense (DVD), undated. (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Indian Tribes - Knowledge, Wisdom and the Traditional Mind: The Nottoway in the 21st Century (DVD), 2014. (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Indian Tribes - Mattaponi, 2016-2019. (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Indian Tribes - Meeting, 2018 Feb 9. (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Indian Tribes - Meeting, 2018 June 22. (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Indian Tribes - Meeting (US Dept. of Health and Human Resources, Region III Tribal Consultation), 2019 Sept 8. (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Indian Tribes - Meeting with Gov. Northam, 2019 Nov 8. (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Indian Tribes - Meeting between Tribes of the Thomasina E. Jordan Act, undated. (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Indian Tribes - Miscellaneous, 2018-2021. (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Indian Tribes - Pocahontas, 2017. (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Indian Tribes - Rassawek Discussion with Monacan Nation Leaders, 2019 July 1. (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Indian Tribes - Repatriation Memorial, 2016. (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Indian Tribes - State Tribal Recognition Project (STEP), 2019-2020. (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Indian Tribes - Tribal initiatives and budget requests, 2021. (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Indian Tribes - Virginia Indians meeting with Sec. Thomasson, 2017 Jan 6. (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Indian Tribes - Virginia Tribes (binder), undated. (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Indian Tribes - Wolf Creek Cherokee Tribe, 2016. (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Invitations, 2018 Jan. (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Invitations, 2018 Feb. (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Invitations, 2018 Mar. (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Invitations, 2018 Apr. (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Invitations, 2018 May. (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Invitations, 2018 June. (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Invitations, 2018 July. (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Invitations, 2018 Aug. (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Invitations, 2018 Sept. (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Invitations, 2018 Oct. (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Invitations, 2018 Nov. (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Invitations, 2018 Dec. (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Invitations, 2019 Feb-Mar. (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Invitations, 2019 Apr-June. (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Invitations, 2019 July-Sept. (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Invitations, 2019 Oct-Dec. (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Invitations, 2020 Jan-Feb. (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Invitations, 2020 Mar-June. (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Invitations, 2021 Sept. (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - License plate requests, 2009-2021. (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Miscellaneous, 2018-2022. (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Notaries, 2018-2021. (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Planning and priorities, undated. (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - Latino Outreach, 2018. (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - Pardons (correspondence), 2018-2019. (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - Pardons (correspondence), 2020. (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Pardons (correspondence), 2021-2022. (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Pardons (correspondence), undated. (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Pardons - Martinsville Seven, 2020-2021. (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Procedures, 2018. (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Restoration of Rights - Meeting, 2019 July 19. (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Seal of Virginia, 2017-2020. (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Virginia Black Leaders Roundtable, 2019 Mar. (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Virginia Black Leaders Roundtable, 2019 Sept. (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Series II: Deputy Secretary of the Commonwealth Traci DeShazor, 2018-2021., Extent: .XX cu. ft.
    XX
    - Authentications, 2018-2019. (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Census, 2019-2020. (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Commission on African American History Education in the Commonwealth - Agenda and oaths, 2019. (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Constituent correspondence, 2018. (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Constituent correspondence, 2019. (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Constituent correspondence, 2021. (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Governor Decision Requests, 2018-2021. (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Maternal Mortality Review Team - Oath, 2020. (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Miscellaneous, 2018-2021. (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Seal of Virginia, 2019-2021. (Box 12, Folder 19)